‎SAY NO TO PIRACY, SUPPORT ORIGINALS
‎ADAPTED FROM XI XING’S NOVEL
‎QUEEN CHU‎ ON QIDIAN.COM
THE GREAT BORDER GATE
The… The Lord of Xiaonan rebelled.
Return at once to tell Her Highness.
Your Highness, Xiao Xun
killed the dispatch riders.
We've lost contact with the Capital.
All post houses along the way
are under his control.
Rumors reached the Capital.
Northern Desert Army
breached Bailang Pass.
Yunzhong will fall in three days.
They'll march for the imperial city.
How's the Capital?
Fifty thousand troops in the capital camp
and one 100,000 nearby.
Why should we fear Xiao Xun?
What we fear is that the commoners
believe Xiao Xun's lie
to defend the Capital.
In that case,
he can rightfully
lead his troops into the city.
If Xiao Xun enters the Capital,
Yu's life will be in danger.
Xie Yanfang is by Yu's side.
He's ruthless.
But his clan relies on Yu.
Xie Yanfang will protect him.
You're right.
Xie Yanfang still has a crucial trick.
This time,
he'll definitely make this move.
Get Xiaoman to me.
Yes.
CHU ZHAO
Whatever you want me to do, let me know.
All post houses along the way
have been cut off.
I want you to take your men
to bypass the post houses
and head for the Capital.
Then, escort my cousin Chu Tang
and her family out of the Capital.
Why all the trouble?
Why don't we let her bring the news
of the frontier to the Capital?
Who would believe a bandit?
The public opinion in the Capital
completely favors Xiao Xun,
who "guards" His Majesty.
Then what is the problem
with Chu Tang's family?
Chu Lan is a mere civil official.
What danger justifies
all the effort to save him?
In the Anping Rebellion,
Xiao Xun used my uncle
to kill His Majesty.
Now, he's the key witness.
All parties will fight over him.
I count on you.
Don't worry. Leave it to me.
What about you? To the Capital?
No.
I'm going somewhere else.
TABLET OF LATE FATHER, CHU LING
TABLET OF LATE MOTHER, MU MIANHONG
Father.
Mother.
You were separated half your lives.
Now you're finally reunited
in the underworld.
Sadly,
I have to leave.
I'll keep defending the city
Father left undefended.
I'll continue the war
Father left unfinished.
Mother dreamed of peace
all over the world.
I'll make it come true.
THE CAPITAL
I've heard Xiao Xun
has reached Baili Pavilion.
A noble heir like him is always reliable.
I believe soon, he'll rescue
the Capital from danger.
He's been practicing martial arts
since childhood,
and he leads elite troops.
I hope he'll arrive soon.
Since General Chu died,
the Yunzhong troops
have been in utter chaos.
They won't bother with the Capital.
Luckily, His Highness is on his way here.
Fair enough.
The Grand Princess is brave,
but she's too young.
We have to count on real royal members
to guard the Capital
and protect our state.
Jiang, the weather is lovely.
Take Tang out for some fresh air.
The tea has gone cold.
The conversation is ironic.
If she stays longer, she'll feel sick.
Goodbye, then.
Jiang.
Why is she angry again?
Mr. Xiao Xun is noble.
Had General Chu not built
the city walls at great cost…
Had Her Highness not guarded Wangcheng…
You couldn't be sitting here,
enjoying cold tea, or satirizing them.
I advise you to hold your tongues.
Jiang, I have a favor to ask.
We're friends. Don't say that. What is it?
I need help from your family.
Mr. Xie, to what do I owe
the honor of this visit?
I'm here to ask you, Mr. Deng.
Do you really choose
to throw your life away with Xiao Xun?
What do you mean?
I don't understand.
Xiao Xun has reached Baili Pavilion.
He keeps releasing messages
that he's coming to protect His Majesty.
He expects a wide-open city gate
where people line up to welcome him.
But do you know how we will end up
if the city gate is open to him?
Since it's the will of people,
you should try to stop
the people in the Capital.
What's the point of coming here
to stop me?
Looks like you're determined
to side with Mr. Xiao.
They're within the defense line.
The Capital is just ahead.
If His Majesty still refuses
to open the gate,
their advance will be an unauthorized move
and willful treason.
After they enter the city,
you might as well
find an excuse to kill them.
You know people's will is irreversible.
In their eyes, Xiao Xun
is a meritorious protector
they're expecting.
If His Majesty still refuses,
people will complain.
So, Mr. Xie, what do you intend to do?
We must make Xiao Xun
a rebel again.
Are you saying
you'll prove his father's treason?
Only in this way
can we stop Xiao Xun from entering town.
If he attacks by force,
all the people will know
that the court has no choice
but to fight back.
If war breaks out,
the court will be rightful.
We'll have no more worries,
and all the people will submit.
Then no one will question
Yu's throne.
Then how will you prove
the treason of the Lord of Xiaonan?
Do you know
Chu Lan was bribed by Xiao Xun
to poison Yu in Chu Mansion?
You'll use Chu Lan as a scapegoat?
Have you considered?
If Chu Lan gets in trouble,
the Chu Family will be implicated.
Then the Grand Princess
can hardly stay out of trouble.
Great achievements
require great sacrifices.
Only when we expose Xiao Xun's scheme
can the two of us
keep the city gate firmly shut.
Isn't that so?
I'm still curious about one thing.
Xiao Xun wrote a letter to you.
What was in…?
After all that talking, I finally get it.
You think Chu Lan isn't enough.
You'll also get me involved
to prove their treason.
But have you thought about this?
Is it a righteous war?
Is it justified?
You care. His Majesty cares.
But I don't care.
Don't try to keep your clan innocent
by ruining my reputation.
You're wrong again.
I just came here to give you a favor.
Instead of keeping some secrets buried,
why not turn them into your achievements?
My Lord.
Xie Yanfang wants to kill two birds
with one stone.
TO OPEN THE GATE OR NOT
Get ready. I'll see Chu Lan tonight.
CHU MANSION
My Lord, we looked everywhere.
No one is in.
We asked the neighbors.
Nothing unusual was noticed.
During the day, Chu Tang
even had tea with some ladies.
As she came home,
she vanished into thin air.
We may have early plans,
but someone's always earlier.
As soon as we had the idea,
they had run away.
How could they leave so perfectly?
Theoretically, when Chu Zhao is away,
Chu Lan should be isolated from the court.
And Chu Lan doesn't look
like he can read the situation.
Is it possible
that Her Highness sent them a message?
Xiao Xun intercepted all the messages.
How did Chu Zhao manage to send one?
Xie Yanfang used up all his schemes.
But his own ally stabbed him in the back.
Send a message to Mr. Xie.
Tell him the witness he longs for
has fled.
XIE RESIDENCE
How come he fled?
The Grand Princess
has more political support
than I imagined.
Of the clans that have ties
with the Chu Family,
five left the city yesterday.
Some said they went to rural houses.
Some said they had an outing. And…
Today, three ladies
met with Chu Tang in the day.
Shall we pursue them?
QI HONGYE EXCELS AT POLITICAL STRATEGY.
ZHOU MINGLI DEVOTES TO BE A SCHOLAR.
It is time for us
to go out and visit someone.
ZHOU FAMILY’S FARMSTEAD
‎ZHOU RESIDENCE
Be careful, Mr. Chu.
Come on, sweetheart.
Hurry. Come, Tang.
Jiang,
-thank you.
-My pleasure.
Don't thank me.
Without my grandfather's approval,
I couldn't have helped you,
even if I wanted to.
Jiang, I need you
to help my family leave.
Why me?
Shouldn't you beg some clan heads?
I was told to ask them,
but big clans have deep connections
with shared interests.
I…
I thought about it.
You're the only one
I can entrust my life to.
At the Hai hour tonight,
my carriage will pick you up
at the back door of Chu Mansion.
I shall remember
your great favor.
Go get some rest.
Come on, Tang.
Your uncle and his daughter
are so useless.
We shouldn't have
expected them to bring glory.
You…
Luckily, our daughter is farsighted
and gets along with other noble ladies.
Madam, you sound so proud.
Do you really think
her mere friendship
can get you through the city defense?
The Grand Princess
arranged deceptive schemes
and sent bandits to clear enemy sentries.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
have come here alive.
-You… You are…
-Yes.
We're the bandits
whom people like you despise most.
Her Highness sent me to get you.
Don't yell.
Nod, and I'll let you go.
The Lord of Xiaonan isn't a defender,
but a usurper.
To reveal Xiao Xun's true colors,
the court will dig up the evidence
your father nearly killed
the young emperor.
Danger.
Her Highness said the heads
of these clans are reliable.
Go ask them for help.
CHU ZHAO
-Darling.
-Xiaoman, let's leave.
This is a bestowal to Jiang's ancestors.
It must be on record
with the Ministry of War.
Within half a day,
we will all get caught.
Tang, how could you
still doubt the Zhou Family?
Just now, Miss Zhou seemed
she truly wanted to help us.
Father, Jiang truly wants to help us.
That's why we can't get her involved.
-But they--
-Stop lingering.
Go with me.
-Let's go. Hurry.
-But they…
Oh, darling.
‎ZHOU BING, MINISTER OF CEREMONIES OF CHU
My Lord, Chu Lan's trail is gone.
Mr. Zhou, you really made
very cunning moves.
No offense,
but I gave up a piece to get ahead.
Mr. Xie,
you're still so enigmatic
when playing Liubo.
I wonder what you're fighting for
in this round.
When the Lord of Xuan played with me,
he wrongfully killed
a loyal man over one piece.
In today's game,
I'm fighting for His Majesty's life.
The Lord of Xiaonan and his heir
nearly took His Majesty's life.
Chu Lan is the witness.
So, I hope you will help His Majesty
to reveal the truth to people.
Over generations, my clan
has been a bystander.
Mr. Xie, you don't need
to probe me like this.
I don't know where Chu Lan is.
Mr. Zhou,
you must know no one can be
a bystander in chaotic times.
My Lord, we've searched. Nothing.
Yes.
Sorry for the offense.
I'll take my leave.
Oh.
It's too windy tonight.
Remember to close your windows.
Mr. Xie, please see yourself out.
My Lady, be careful.
Father.
The carriage that took them
out of town is back.
Shall we make early preparations?
If Mr. Xie really
finds out something, then…
Jiang did something reckless.
But since we promised to help,
we won't complain.
Between the Grand Princess
and Mr. Xie, there will be
a long game of strategy.
XIE RESIDENCE
Welcome, Mr. Deng.
We are honored by your presence.
This orchid is very delicate.
No strangers shall touch it.
You tend this flower so well.
Sadly, its roots have rotted.
It barely appears to bloom.
You've searched the whole day.
Have you found what you're after?
The Grand Princess is so far away,
but big clans give her generous support.
She does have great influence.
You didn't come here
just to satirize me, did you?
Do you know where Chu Zhao is?
She's riding at full speed toward Xiaonan.
Does she think Xiao Xun
will retreat when his father is trapped?
How childish.
Her Highness will suppress the rebels
on His Majesty's behalf.
What's wrong with it?
Her Highness has great influence.
Since she dares,
she must be confident enough.
Yeah.
You and Her Highness
used to have the same goal.
You were both against Xiao Xun.
But you insist on using
Chu Lan as a scapegoat
and getting her clan involved.
Obviously,
Chu Zhao wouldn't agree.
That's a bit much, Mr. Deng.
As long as you approve the edict
that Xiao Xun instigated Chu Lan
to poison the imperial grandson,
Her Highness will be
suppressing the rebels
with a valid reason.
I'm helping her, aren't I?
Have you heard about this?
An orchid dies,
but its fragrance will linger.
Someone
only gets in the way when he's alive.
Mr. Xie, you have
a very clever plan.
I'll take my leave.
Mr. Deng.
We're just serving the state
by cutting out the deadwood.
‎EDICT TO DEPOSE THE RENEGADE OFFICIAL
What's this?
Why is Zhao guilty?
Don't, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
this edict says
her uncle Chu Lan is guilty.
Did you forget?
He tried to poison you back then.
So, Her Highness
took you away from her family.
So, Chu Lan is really guilty.
Then why did no one tell me about it?
Chu Lan is Zhao's uncle.
If he's guilty, she will be implicated.
Now, the situation is complicated.
Lord of Xiaonan and his heir
intend rebellion.
Xiao Xun is coming as a defender.
Our people support him.
Ministers want the city gate
to be opened too.
But if he leads
his 100,000 troops into town
without firing a single shot,
we won't be able to resist.
The casualties will be terrible.
What we should do now
is let the entire world know
the sins of Xiao Xun and his father.
Then we'll all rise against them.
You're bullying Zhao.
You're bullying her
just because her father is gone.
Yu,
no one is bullying your sister.
If she were here now,
she would do the same.
The post houses have been cut off.
But the men I sent out learnt something.
Xiao Xun intercepted a victory report.
Not long ago,
Chu Zhao led a raid
against Northern Desert Royal Army,
driving them back a hundred li.
And later,
the enemy relaunched an attack.
Once again, she led troops to crush them.
She did?
What's more,
on hearing Xiao Xun was leading troops
to surround the Capital,
she led forces to attack Xiaonan.
Do you know why?
"Besiege Wei to rescue Zhao."
I've read about that.
That's right.
So you don't need to worry.
Your sister fears nothing.
No one can bully her easily.
She's defending our state and our people.
Even when her uncle is guilty,
she won't be implicated.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
CHU LAN PLOTTED REGICIDE WITH XIAO XUN.
TITLES REVOKED. ASSETS SEIZED. IMPRISONED.
XIAONAN PREFECTURE
I never thought
I could have a battle
against the Grand Princess.
How dare she besiege us
with only a few thousand troops?
A warrior's daughter?
I think the great reputation of Chu Ling
will just be ruined by his daughter
who has a swollen head.
Your Lordship, don't bother with her.
I'll go teach her a lesson.
Your Lordship, the Grand Princess
wants to talk.
The Grand Princess? What's she doing here?
Since she wants to talk,
tell her I have trouble walking
and can't go out.
However, my gate is always open to her.
She can come anytime.
XIAONAN
We both know it's an ambush.
If you enter his mansion,
you'll be walking
straight into the lion's den.
If Xiaonan holds you as a hostage,
the Capital will face a tough choice.
You worry too much.
Mr. Deng and Xie Yanfang
can't wait for me to die for the state.
Believe it or not,
they've even prepared my posthumous title.
This is no child's play.
Are you really sure?
I know what worries you.
The Lord of Xiaonan is so cunning
that he even rebels
in the name of guarding His Majesty.
If the Grand Princess dies in his mansion,
guess how history will judge him.
He will be a traitor,
whether he likes it or not.
So…
Will you take this gamble with me?
Of course.
Not to mention his mansion,
I'll even follow you
to the underworld.
This time,
we'll all live well.
We must live.
XIAONAN
What an impressive mansion.
Look at the scale.
He's so obviously showing
his ambition to be the Emperor.
Then, I'll kill that hope of his.
WEILIAOZI: ON MILITARY STRATEGY
How could we reject the tea he offered?
You've got some spine, Miss Chu.
Don't you fear I may put something
in the tea?
I am the Grand Princess of State.
I can fight battles with you
and slaughter your men.
If I were to die from poisoned tea,
people in the world would laugh at you.
Even if I were bloodthirsty,
I would know I should keep
worthy generals alive.
Besides, I've admired General Chu.
He's gone.
I still count on you
to inherit his legacy.
How would I try to kill you?
You flatter me.
In that case,
please withdraw your troops
that are besieging the Capital.
Don't let common folks die
in your fight for the throne.
As a general's daughter,
you must be familiar
with military classics.
Have you read about this?
Glory for one, death for thousands.
New dynasty rises, the old one falls.
Someone must sweep away the incense ash
before burning new incense.
If His Majesty grants you the Golden Seal
and feudal sovereignty,
will you stop the war?
Your Highness, when His Lordship
can get the Imperial Seal,
why would he need the Golden Seal?
You offered a great deal
to make me retreat.
But how dare a woman like you
grant me feudal sovereignty?
When I grant something, you will get it.
Now, I understand.
You aren't persuading me
for the young emperor
or the ministers in the court.
You're trying to stop me
for the sake of the people.
What a saint you are.
I'm not a saint.
I am the Grand Princess of State.
I won't see this state fall apart.
Like I said,
I've admired General Chu,
and I think highly of you.
What about
you and I working together?
How?
If I become the Emperor,
Xun will be the Crown Prince,
and you'll be the Crown Princess.
Then you'll be the Empress.
I can also grant you
the command over frontier troops,
unrestrained by the court's Tally.
Do you agree?
So, being Xiao Xun's empress
can get me such great power.
I'm not kidding.
I know.
You really mean it.
Too bad, though.
Am I offering not enough?
Feel free to make any other requests.
I have only one request.
I request you to stop the war.
You need to understand one thing.
I can persuade you.
You're in no position to persuade me.
I'm not here to persuade you,
but threaten you.
With what can you threaten me?
Xiao Xun.
Speaking of him,
he has still kept your birthdate card.
He knelt for three days and nights,
swearing to marry no one but you.
But you requested
to annul your engagement.
Xun still hasn't figured out
what he did wrong.
Today,
I know the answer.
You must be Commander Xie.
I've heard a lot about you.
You're as remarkable as people say.
During the coup,
you led a few guards
to defeat ten thousand troops.
You are a real hero.
Your Lordship, don't be ridiculous.
I broke off my engagement
for the people of our state,
not for romance.
Narrow-minded as you are,
how can you fight for the throne?
What a sharp tongue.
If I remember correctly, Mr. Xie,
your brother also has great ambitions.
If one day you meet in armed conflict,
whose side will you take?
I pledge loyalty to His Majesty,
the Grand Princess,
and the State of Chu.
Anyone who hurts the imperial heir
or the Grand Princess
will be my enemy.
You're truly a hero
who is worth a hundred men.
Remarkable, indeed.
Do you know he isn't the only one
who is worth a hundred?
There's also the Longwei Army.
The Longwei Army?
You must've heard about the Longwei Army.
They put down the rebellion
while outnumbered.
My father devotedly trained them.
They move like ghosts
and scatter around in disguise.
How can you be sure
there aren't any in your mansion?
If you agree to retreat,
I'll pretend nothing happened.
So, this is how you threaten me.
You want to use the Longwei Army
to kill my son as well as me.
You can take this as a gamble.
Five thousand soldiers outside the town.
Five thousand of the Longwei Army in town.
If they join hands,
how will you handle it?
Someone.
Get the rooms ready.
Give Her Highness a warm reception.
The secret guards in this room
can be withdrawn.
With poor inner power and uneven breath,
they're useless.
Your Lordship, Xie Yanlai
is no ordinary man.
When he's around Chu Zhao,
we can hardly hurt her.
Ning Kun, you have no idea.
Chu Ling and the late emperor
trained the Longwei Army.
The scariest thing about them is,
we don't know who they are,
and we don't know
when or where they'll appear.
They're unpreventable.
Tell Xun to be on guard.
Yes.
In such a big courtyard,
I can't even hear a bird.
It's eerily quiet.
Careful.
Lord of Xiaonan has great taste.
He even uses the best tea
for mere visitors.
Too bad, though. The tea got cold.
We know it's an ambush,
and we should be more cautious.
What if he poisoned the tea?
He wouldn't dare.
Not now, at least.
What he wants is to be legitimate.
If I die in his place, have a guess.
Will people spit and drown this place?
You know the Longwei Army
isn't in Xiaonan,
but you bluffed just like that.
Didn't you fear that he could
see through you?
Let me tell you this.
What makes the Longwei Army terrifying
is that people believe they're everywhere.
Don't worry.
Someone's having a harder time.
His Lordship is cautious by nature.
Without a perfect plan,
he wouldn't act rashly.
He sent Xiao Xun to the Capital
because he thought the time was right.
The calmer we are,
the more he will doubt his own judgment.
When he thinks it's not the right time,
he'll ask Xiao Xun to retreat.
So, just now, you were trying
to break his will,
making him think his plan wasn't perfect.
Then he'll lose his cool
-and withdraw.
-That's right.
So, Jiu, don't be impatient.
We'll just wait.
We'll wait patiently
until he makes his decision.
I've heard this is the best scenic spot
all over this mansion.
Let's not waste his hospitality.